字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
最快首发美剧日剧下载请登录
字幕组网站www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译：王大可 想名字好难 小暴徒 木浅 kahiko
翻译：dzysteven JohnnyG 勾勾  校对：油炸电风扇   木浅薰
时间轴：壬虚浪影  苏菲  BIU
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第六季   第九集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
我让加洛以敲诈罪的名义进了监狱
I put Gallo away for racketeering.
但这并不是他真正的罪行
But that's not what he really did.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
我们发现他参与了谋杀案
We had him for conspiracy to commit murder,
警方把他供认的录像带
and the police let the tape of that bastard admitting
落在证据链外二十分钟  有意让证据无效
that he did it out of the chain of custody for 20 minutes.
你有不在场证明的证人
You had an alibi witness,
然而你的公诉人却让她走掉了
and your public defender let her get away?
我一直都是这么说的啊
That's what I've been saying!
我并没有一个能做不在场证明的证人
I didn't have an alibi witness.
证人凭空消失了
I had a no-show who vanished into thin air.
你至少可以
Well, you could've asked for
要求延期受审来找到她
postponement to have time to find her.
我是可以  只是还有个小问题
And I would have, except for one thing:
当我要求她说出事发那时他们
when I pressed her as to what the two of them
两个人在做什么
were doing at the time of those murders,
她承认说他们吸了冰毒
she admitted they were both on meth.
加洛的动议被退回来了
Gallo's filing came back,
这个动议需要由其辩护律师本人提出
and it needs to be filed by his attorney of record.
你要我代理那个野兽
You want me to represent that animal?
其实挺好笑的  不是吗
Kind of funny, isn't it?
当初你花大力气把我弄进来
You fighting to get me out
现在你想要弄我出去
when you fought so hard to put me away.
我确实觉得很恶心
It makes me sick to my stomach,
但你会给我回报的
but you're gonna give me something in return.
你不仅不能找迈克的麻烦
Not only are you gonna keep your hands off Mike,
还要做他的私人保镖
you're gonna be his personal protector in here.
你让我妻子免受牢狱之灾
You kept my wife out of prison.
在我看来  我们已经扯平了
As far as I'm concerned, that makes us square.
哈维和迈克成功了
Harvey and Mike did it,
意味着迈克能回家了
which means Mike's coming home.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
约书亚来了电话
Joshua called.
他明天要来城里住两天
He's coming to town tomorrow.
你要跟他分手吗
Are you gonna break up with him?
我不知道
I don't know.
很感谢你能这么做
I really appreciate you doing this.
如果你没有在这里陪我
and... if you weren't with me,
我很难想象自己如何承受
I can't imagine how I'd handle
塔拉不知到底会不会和约书亚分手这件事
whether or not Tara is breaking up with Joshua.
约书亚  这是什么名字
Joshua--what is he?
某个傻缺国的国王吗
Lord of the Kingdom of Dicken-stein,
统治着傻缺山头上的臣民
reigning over his subjects from high atop Douche Mountain?
总之谢谢你能来
Anyway, thanks for being here.
除了塔拉
Aside from Tara,
你是我生命中最重要的女人
you're the most important woman in my entire life.
我的天哪  路易
Oh, my God, Louis.
泥浴真是
Mudding is...
太爽了
amazing.
刚刚这半个小时我都睡着了
I actually just fell asleep for the last half hour.
天哪  唐娜
Goddamn it, Donna.
我带你来不是让你在我
I didn't bring you here so you could fall asleep
向你吐露心声时睡觉的
while I'm pouring my heart out.
你是我见过最自私的女人
You're the most selfish woman I ever met.
我以为你刚说过我是你人生中除了塔拉以外
I thought you just told me I was the most important
最重要的女人
non-Tara woman in your life.
等等  你不是睡着了吗
Wait a second. I thought you just fell asleep.
刚刚这三十秒
And for the last thirty seconds,
你是在生我的气还是生约书亚的气
have you been mad at me or upset about Joshua?
天哪  你真是个天才
Holy shit, you're a genius.
所以等我们回到了办公室
Which is why when we get back to the office,
你要负责匹配
you're reconciling everyone's billings
所有人最近六周的账单
for the last six weeks.
唐娜  那是我所能经历的
Oh, Donna, that is the worst form of torture
最残酷的折磨了
I can go through.
不  路易  对你来说
No, Louis, the worst form of torture
最残酷的折磨是脑子里面
is what you'll do if you don't have something
没有事情可想
to occupy your mind.
我的天哪  你说得对
Oh, my God, you're right.
我不在乎价格
I don't care what the cost
以及我在泥里面什么也没穿
or that I'm entirely naked underneath this mud.
我要再加一个小时
I'm getting us another hour.
路易  罗纳德回来
Louis, you are not moving another centimeter
把帘子挂上之前
until Renaldo comes back in here
你一厘米都不要再动了
and puts that privacy curtain back up.
看看谁来了
Oh, look who's here.
我应该要到下午才能出去的
I'm not supposed to get out till this afternoon,
-所以你还剩  -迈克  坐下
- but leave it to you to-- - Mike, sit down.
好吧
Okay.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
卡荷尔打电话说
Cahill called and said
你的释放出了些问题
there was a problem with your release.
不是什么大事
It's not a big deal,
只是时间要更长一点
but it's just gonna take a little longer.
-还要多长  -还要几天
- How much longer? - A few days.
哈维  我告发了某人
Harvey, I informed on someone.
如果传出去
If word gets out about that--
你以为我不知道吗
You think I don't know that?
但他撤销了你的协议  之后又恢复了
But he pulled your deal then reinstated it.
所以时间要长一些
It's gonna take a little time.
那与此同时我要怎么办
Well, what the hell am I supposed to do in the meantime?
老实呆着  保持警惕
Sit tight, and keep your wits about you.
你都坚持了这么久
You made it this long.
多几天一定没问题
You can make it a few more days.
瑞秋知道这件事了吗
Does Rachel know about this?
她本来就不知道
Look, she didn't know it was gonna take this long
你要多久才能出去
in the first place,
我觉得现在也没必要告诉她
and I didn't see the need to tell her now.
那就帮个忙别跟她说了
Do me a favor, and let's keep it that way.
瑞秋  早上好
Rachel, good morning.
我之前还找你来着
I was looking for you before.
我想恭喜你迈克就要出来了
I wanted to say congratulations on getting Mike out.
谢谢
I appreciate that.
但我们还有些别的好消息
But we have some other good news.
我们也许也要把伦纳德・贝利救出来了
We may be on our way to getting Leonard Bailey out too.
你找到方法让法院重审了吗
Did you figure out a way to reopen the trial?
是的
I did.
瑞秋  理论上来说是不错的
Rachel, this is good in theory,
但这没有先例
but there's no precedent.
有的
Yes, there is.
特纳诉密歇根州政府
Turner versus the State of Michigan.
你是怎么找到这个的
How the hell did you find that?
助理做久了
It turns out being a paralegal for so long
会很擅长大海捞针
was a blessing in disguise,
因为没人比我更擅长搜寻线索
because nobody is better at research than me.
非常好  起草一份申诉书
Great. Write up a declaration,
做完尽快交给我
and get it to me as soon as you're done.
接下来的事交给我
And I'll get this thing rolling.
杰西卡  我以为我可以负责做这件事
Jessica, I thought I'd be the one to do it.
瑞秋  你还不是个律师
Rachel, you're not a lawyer yet.
我不用成为律师
I don't need to be.
她是她的公设辩护律师  她会处理的
She's his public defender. She'll do this for us.
听我说  有时事情并不能像计划那样进行
Listen to me--sometimes things don't go exactly as planned.
没人比你更擅长搜寻线索
And nobody is better at research than you,
但没人比我更擅长让事情尘埃落定
but nobody is better at dropping the hammer than me.
听我说  我要问你个问题
Listen to me, I'm gonna ask you a question,
我需要知道真相
and I need to know the truth.
你知道卡荷尔干的好事吗
You know about this Cahill shit?
卡荷尔干什么好事了
What Cahill shit?
很显然萨特无法满足那个混蛋了
Apparently Sutter wasn't enough for that asshole,
因为他冻结了我们的资产
because he's been seizing our assets left and right.
你真的觉得他们会让她
You really think they were gonna let her
留着在进行内幕交易时赚到的直接收益吗
keep direct proceeds from insider trading?
我不是说直接收益
I'm not talking about direct proceeds.
我是说我们拥有的一切
I'm talking about everything we have.
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yeah,
包括她在
including money she earned
被卷入这烂摊子之前挣的钱
before she ever got wrapped up in that bullshit.
他们不能这么做
They can't do that.
但他们正在做
Well, they're doing it.
我不管你在这还是出去以后
And I don't care whether you do something about it
是否要做点什么
from in here or when you get out there,
但是你说服我们签了协议  迈克
but you're the one who convinced us to take this deal, Mike,
所以你最好想办法阻止
so you better damn well be the one to stop it.
大律师
Hey, Counselor.
你没忘了我吧
You didn't forget about me, did you?
你的听证会是明天下午两点
Your hearing's tomorrow at 2:00.
我给你发过文件了
I sent you the paperwork.
正好赶在最后一刻
Right under the wire.
时间安排得挺紧啊
Cutting it close, huh?
我说过我会弄好的  现在弄好了  加洛
I said I'd get it done, and it's done, Gallo.
-现在我要走了  -这么快
- Now I'm leaving. - So soon?
我以为你要跟我见面谈谈策略的
I thought you might want to meet and chat strategy.
我的策略是明天让你拿到假释
My strategy is for you to get your parole tomorrow
然后把你从我的记忆中抹掉
and then burn your existence from my brain.
我不喜欢你跟你客户的
I don't think I like the way you just spoke
讲话方式  哈维
to your own client, Harvey.
你最好能成功
You better come through.
我会成功的  加洛
I'll come through, Gallo,
但你最好记住你那部分协议
but you better remember your part of the deal.
什么  保护迈克吗
What, protecting Mike?
如果我和他友好相处  他还需要什么保护
What does Mike need protecting for if I'm cool with him?
你少扯淡了
Save your bullshit.
我清楚你知道了迈克一直在告密
I know you know Mike was informing.
没错  我还知道威廉・萨特要完蛋
Yeah, I also know William Sutter's going away,
也就是说迈克要出狱了
which means Mike's getting out.
他还没出来呢
Well, he's not out yet,
既然你俩现在都在里面
so while you're both still in there,
你给我看好他
you don't take your eyes off him.
我向来说话算数
I'm nothing if not a man of my word.
还有哈维  我不想穿这一身
Oh, and Harvey, I don't want to stand
站在假释委员会面前
of the parole board wearing this,
给我带件像样的衣服穿
so bring me something nice to wear.
我进来的时候穿修身版38号
I was a 38 slim when I came in.
现在估计要穿普通版40号
Now I'm more like a 40 reg.
你来决定吧  毕竟你穿的这么讲究
I'll leave it up to you; you're the dandy.
我是肖恩・卡荷尔
This is Sean Cahill.
肖恩  我是迈克・罗斯
Well, Sean, this is Mike Ross.
有什么事吗  迈克
What can I do for you, Mike?
你可以告诉我为什么
You can tell me why the hell
你要冻结吉尔・米勒的资产吗
you're going after Jill Miller's assets.
对不起  我不知道你是她的会计
I'm sorry, I wasn't aware you were her accountant.
如果你不停手的话
Well, if you don't back off,
我就要成她的律师了
I'm about to become her goddamn lawyer.
-你说什么  -她的协议里没有这块
- Excuse me? - That wasn't part of her deal.
是没有  但我不会让她
No, it wasn't, but I'm not gonna let her
拿着通过犯罪得来的钱
keep her money she made committing a crime.
你不只是拿走了她犯罪得来的钱
You're not just taking money she made from a crime.
你把她这些年在公司
You're taking the salary she made
挣的薪水全拿走了
from working at that company for years.
听着  这个女人逃过了坐牢
Listen, that woman got out of going to prison.
但是每次他们买进股票
But every time they took a position,
都会让那些失去了一切的人赔钱
they sold the other side to people who lost everything.
工人们的生活已经毁于一旦了
And I'll be damned if I let her live high on the hog
我能让她滋润地过日子才怪
while working people's lives were ruined.
肖恩  我知道你母亲和西班牙的事情
Sean, I know about your mother and Spain.
但不是吉尔・米勒拿走了她的钱
But Jill Miller didn't take her money.
我不关心  我有能力这么做
I don't care. And I have the power to do this.
谈话结束
And this conversation is over.
杰西卡・皮尔逊
Jessica Pierson.
我秘书本该告诉你我不接新客户了
My secretary should've told you I'm not taking new clients.
这么说你知道我来这里的原因
I take it you know why I'm here.
你的徒弟指责我没有尽责为莱纳德・贝利辩护
I tried to be polite when your protégé accused me
我尽量保持克制
of not doing my job with Leonard Bailey.
但我可不会听一个雇佣冒牌货的人
But I'm not gonna be told by someone who harbored a fraud
说我是多差的一个律师
what a bad lawyer I am.
我认为你不是个坏律师  乔治娜
I don't think you're a bad lawyer, Georgina.
我认为你是一个犯了错的好律师
I think you're a good lawyer that made a mistake.
我来这里是为了给你个机会弥补的
And I'm here to give you a chance to fix it.
说来听听
And how's that?
伦纳德・贝利不在场证明的证人死了
Leonard Bailey's alibi witness is dead.
这不代表她的证词不存在
That doesn't mean her testimony is.
你想让我给她告诉我的事作证吗
You want me to testify to what she told me?
这是道听途说
That would be hearsay.
如果她没死  没错
It would be if she were alive.
但现在她死了
But now that she's dead...
她是个无法传唤的申诉人
She's an unavailable declarant.
如我所说  你是个好律师
Like I said, you are a good lawyer.
我不会假装我曾让一个活生生的证人消失了
And I'm not pretending I let a solid witness disappear
而那个姑娘是个瘾君子
when that girl was a junkie
而她的故事最多也就是前后矛盾
and her story was inconsistent at best.
但仍应该向陪审团陈述这件事
And it still should've been presented to a jury,
这正是我们想修正的
which is what we're trying to fix.
你唯一想修正的就是你的名声
The only thing you're trying to fix is your reputation.
但你不能通过玷污我的名声达到目的
And you're not doing it by smearing mine.
乔治娜  有人命悬一线
Georgina, a man's life is on the line.
可我当初已经尽我所能为他辩护了
And I did my best to defend it,
我现在没有义务再做一遍
but I have no obligation to do it again.
那你就错了
That's where you're wrong.
我徒弟冒昧地起草了一份宣誓证明
My protégé took the liberty of drawing up a sworn affidavit
里面陈述了玛利亚・戈麦斯告诉过你
which states Maria Gomez told you
伦纳德・贝利不可能谋杀了那对夫妻
Leonard Bailey couldn't have murdered that couple
因为他俩当时在一起
because he was with her at the time.
现在你要么签了它
Now you can either sign it,
要么在宣誓后撒谎说这是假的
or you lie under oath that this isn't true.
相信我  你不想在出庭作证时
And believe you me, you do not want to be on that stand
当着我的面向陪审团撒谎
lying to a jury and have to face me.
唐娜  取消我明天所有的预约
Donna, cancel all my meetings tomorrow,
然后告诉假释委员会加洛准备好了
and notify the parole board that Gallo's ready.
-哈维  -我不想听
- Harvey-- - I don't want to hear it.
听我说
Listen to me.
我和你一起把他送进监狱的
I was there with you when you put him away,
如果我不提醒一下你当初你对他的评价的话
and I wouldn't be able to live with myself
我是不会心安理得的
if I didn't remind you what you said about him at the time.
我不需要你提醒
I don't need reminding.
你说过他是一个
You said he was a sociopath
以伤害他人为乐的反社会者
who took pleasure from hurting people.
唐娜  我没有选择的余地
Donna, I don't have a choice.
这是你知道迈克要出狱之前的事
That was before you knew that Mike was getting out.
如果你骗他几个小时
If you just string him along for a couple more hours--
迈克今天出不来了
Mike's not getting out today.
什么
What?
卡荷尔给我打电话了
Cahill called me.
协议需要过几天才能通过
The deal's gonna take a few more days to go through.
如果加洛以为我在骗他
And if Gallo even thinks that I'm stringing him along,
迈克可能永远都出不来了
Mike may never get out of there at all.
我会给你空出时间的
I'll clear your schedule.
我需要和你谈谈
Hey, I need to talk to you.
谈之前
Before you do,
我只想说之前我不是
I just want to say i didn't mean to
故意把一切怪罪于你的
put it all on you earlier.
现在这不重要  听着
No, that doesn't matter now. Listen.
你说过当初你被捕时
You said that when you got arrested,
你拒绝了一份供出萨特的协议
you turned down a deal to turn on Sutter.
我需要知道他们是怎么说的
I need to know exactly what they said.
我不明白这和吉尔有什么关系
I don't understand what that has to do with Jill.
没关系
It doesn't.
这和我要把你弄出监狱
It has to do with the fact that
有关系
I'm trying to get you out of here.
什么
What?
钱的事我也许无能为力
I might not be able to do anything about the money,
但也许我能做的
but maybe what I can do
是让你和家人团聚
is make it so that you can be with your family.
不了
No.
-为什么说不  -不用了
- What do you mean, no? - No.
他们已经盯着我们的钱了
They're already going after our money.
我不想让自己的行为
I don't want to do anything
破坏吉尔的协议
that's gonna mess with Jill's deal.
听我说  那个协议已经定死了
Listen to me. That deal is as solid as a rock.
我亲自写的  他们不会对她毁约
I wrote it myself; they can't take it away from her
同样也不会对我毁约的
any more than they can take my deal away from me.
但你要告诉我卡荷尔让你供出萨特时
But you need to tell me exactly what Cahill said to you
到底跟你说了什么
when he told you to turn on Sutter.
什么也没说  他从没对我说过话
Nothing. He never said anything to me.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
我这辈子就没和肖恩・卡荷尔说过话
I'm telling you I've never spoken to Sean Cahill in my life.
我来了
All right, I'm here.
我给了你们七天时间寻找那位证人
But I gave you seven days to find that witness,
可你们却背着我行事
and then you went behind my back,
所以你们最好有充分的理由
so you better have a good reason why you're in here
告诉我为什么要来申请重审
asking to reopen this case.
理由我们有  法官大人
We do, Your Honor.
我们找到了伦纳德・贝利的不在场证明
We found Leonard Bailey's alibi.
她们找到的只是传闻证据
What they found is nothing but hearsay.
他这话什么意思
What is he talking about?
他的意思是  我们的目击证人
He's talking about the fact that our eyewitness
三年前就去世了
died three years ago,
但贝利先生的原审律师
and Mr. Bailey's original attorney
将会参照特纳诉密歇根州政府案中
is going to testify on her behalf
有关传闻证据例外情况的规定亲自出庭作证
under the Turner v. Michigan exception to the hearsay rule.
那个案子中有一份书面声明
That exception involved a written statement.
的确有书面声明  但我们这也有
It is a written statement, and we have it right here.
那根本不是书面声明
That is not a written statement.
那只是她今早才胡编的
That is a bullshit affidavit
狗屁承诺
she cobbled together this morning.
你指控人家什么
What did you just accuse her of?
抱歉  法官大人  但我觉得这也太凑巧了
I'm sorry, Your Honor, but I find it decidedly convenient
她们提交的证人证言
that they don't have the witness statement
既没写在笔记本或纸上
written down on a notebook or a scrap of paper
也非案发时期证据
from the same decade that it happened.
可我们却觉得这太不凑巧了
Well, we happen to find it decidedly inconvenient.
乔治娜・凯西之所以当时没写下来
And Georgina Casey didn't write it down at the time
是因为她在代理时
because she didn't do an adequate job
没有做充分的准备
representing her client.
你们的意思是本案由于伦纳德・贝利的
Are you now saying that this case needs to be reopened
代理人工作不充分  应予以重审吗
based on Leonard Bailey having inadequate representation?
这可是对律师同仁
Because that is a serious allegation
十分严厉的指控
to make about a fellow attorney.
我们之前没打算这样做
That wasn't our plan.
但如果这样能给他一个机会
But if that's what it takes to give this man a chance
证明他的清白
to prove his innocence,
那我们就一定会这样做
then it sure as hell is our plan now.
真是荒唐
This is ridiculous.
听起来也许荒唐  但如果她们
It may sound ridiculous, but if they were able to get
能让一位知名律师承认重大过错
a successful attorney to admit to a huge blunder,
那我就要裁定此案还是要重新审查
then I'm ruling that this case should be reopened after all.
卡梅隆  你怎么来了
Cameron, what are you doing here?
你知道我为什么来
You know what I'm doing here.
你是不是疯了  给弗兰克・加洛当代理人
Are you out of your goddamn mind representing Frank Gallo?
-你不懂  -我怎么不懂
- You don't understand. - I understand plenty.
-不  听我说  -不  你听我说
- No, listen to me. - No, you listen to me.
那个混蛋是杀人犯
That guy was a murdering piece of shit
应该被关一辈子
who should've been put away for life,
可你现在却想把他捞出来
and now you're trying to get him out?
他跟迈克・罗斯关在一起
He's in there with Mike Ross.
我才不在乎
I don't care.
我在乎  因为如你所言
Well, I do, because like you just said,
那个混蛋的确是杀人犯
he is a murdering piece of shit.
但你不知道的是  我跟他有了约定
But what you don't know is, I made a deal with him,
我也不会打破这个约定
and I'm not gonna break it.
-我会  -这由不得你
- Then I will. - It's not up to you.
我把这个
Well, it will be
在假释裁决委面前一放  就由得我了
when I play this for the parole board.
那是什么
What is that?
录音中他承认了
It's the tape we had of him admitting
是他杀掉了那个你辜负了的人
that he murdered that man that you shit the bed with
且被排除在证据之外
and got excluded from evidence.
我没辜负任何人  这你是知道的
I didn't shit the bed with anything, and you know it.
你要是敢把这东西带到听证会上
You try to bring that bullshit to his hearing,
我就在你按下播放键前给你赶出去
I'll march you out of there before you get to hit play,
之前法庭没有采信
'cause it wasn't admissible in court,
听证会也不会被采信
and it's not admissible there.
你怎么安慰自己都可以
You tell yourself whatever you want,
但我还是要竭尽全力
but I'm gonna do whatever I need to do
不让那家伙走出监狱
to keep that bastard behind bars.
能谈谈吗
Talk to you a second?
没问题
Of course.
你说得对
You were right.
我刚才工作的时候
The whole time I was working,
塔拉和他的事完全没影响到我...
I didn't worry about what Tara was doing with...
也就是说  我人生第一次
him, which meant the first time in my life,
打破了整理收费表时间的记录
I finished the billables in record time.
可现在你却不敢回家了
And now you're afraid to go home.
我会忍不住去想这件事
I can't help wondering what's happening.
路易  你听过那个千斤顶的故事吗
Louis, have you ever heard of a jack story?
-没有  -那你该听听
- No. - Well, it's time you did.
一个人在乡村公路上爆胎了
A man gets a flat tire on a country road.
他看到远处有间房子
He sees a house in the distance.
他走向那栋房子  一边走
He walks up to the house, and along the way,
他一边想  "他们要是没有千斤顶怎么办"
he starts thinking, "What if they don't have a jack?
"如果他们有
"What if they have a jack,
却管我要钱  假如他们要钱
but they want to charge me for it, and if they do,
会管我要多少
How much would they charge?
一百块  两百块还是一千块"
$100, $200, $1,000?"
-都是废话  -没错
- That's bullshit. - Exactly.
他来到房子面前
So by the time the man gets to the house,
按了门铃  里面的人开了门
rings the bell, and they answer the door,
他却跟他们说
he tells them, "You know what?
"留着你那破千斤顶吧"
Keep your goddamn jack."
-真是机智  -明白我要说什么了吗
- That's brilliant. - So you get my point.
没有
No.
路易  你不知道塔拉的想法
Louis, you have no idea what's going on in Tara's mind,
所以最好的办法就是信任她
so the best thing you can do is trust her.
如果不信任她  我敢肯定
Because if you don't, I'm telling you,
你一定会作出
you're gonna do something that you'll regret
让你遗憾终身的事
for the rest of your life.
好吧  唐娜
All right, Donna.
我等塔拉给我打电话
I'll wait for Tara to call.
很好
Okay.
有何贵干
Can I help you?
你能干什么  叛徒
Help me what, rat?
你说什么
What did you just say?
我说你背叛了自己的室友
I said you ratted on your own roommate.
这事都传开了
Word's spreading,
总有一天
and there's going to come a time
你也会需要我的保护
when you need my protection,
可我却不会管你的
and I won't be there.
发生什么事了
Hey, what's going on here?
没事
Nothing.
怎么会没事  你刚才在威胁他
It's not nothing. You were threatening him.
你再敢不经过我的许可这么做
You ever do it again without my say so,
我就让你后悔认识了我
you'll regret the day you met me.
对不起  弗兰克
Sorry, Frank.
别担心  小子  有我保护你
Don't worry about it, kid. I got your back.
你才不会
No, you don't.
大家都知道狱警是最后知道这些事的
Everyone knows guards are the last one to find out anything.
所以如果大家真知道了
So if word were spreading,
也不可能是狱警来告诉我
I wouldn't be finding out about it from him.
他这么做是因为听命于你
He just did that because you told him to,
因为你想提醒我如果哈维不把你弄出去
because you want to remind me of what's gonna happen
我会有什么后果
if Harvey lets you down.
那我想你应该理解的很透彻了
Well, then, I guess you got the message loud and clear.
祝我明天听证会顺利吧
Good luck to me on my hearing tomorrow.
我让你办的事办了吗
Did you do what I asked you to do?
-办了  -那最好
- I did. - You better.
因为如果你不说人话
Because if you don't sound like a human being,
那就得继续在这儿待两年
you're gonna be in here for another two years.
卡梅隆・丹尼斯来这儿干什么
The hell is Cameron Dennis doing here?
他的事我来处理
You let me worry about him.
斯佩克特先生  请开始吧
Mr. Specter, please proceed.
听证席的女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen of the board,
加洛先生已经服刑十二年
Mr. Gallo has served 12 years
而且表现良好
as an exemplary inmate.
我们希望您能允许
We ask that you release him
让他在监狱外继续他的生活
so he can continue to live his life outside these walls.
但在决定前
But before you decide on that,
请先听听他自己的陈述
we think it's best if you hear from him in his own words.
你个混蛋  这是什么
You son of a bitch, what the hell is this?
这是代表我的委托人  凯文・米勒提出的动议
It's an action on behalf of my client, Kevin Miller.
你去年找他麻烦是滥用权力的行为
You abused your power when you went after him last year.
我才没有滥用
I didn't abuse shit.
我不敢苟同
I beg to differ.
因为凯文不仅住在新泽西
'Cause not only does Kevin live in New Jersey,
车祸也发生在那里
but his accident was there too,
也就是说你越权管了其他地域的事
which means you were outside of your jurisdiction.
你最好撤回这个动议
You better rescind this suit,
因为如果他们找我的麻烦
because if they come after me--
他们不会找你麻烦的  肖恩
They're not gonna come after you, Sean,
因为我还没有提出
because I haven't filed it yet.
我也不会提出  只要你同意救凯文出去
And I'm not going to, as long as you agree to get Kevin out.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
-我不会这么做的  -为什么
- I'm not gonna do that. - Why not?
因为我不会被
'Cause I'm not gonna get held hostage
你这种人威胁
by the likes of you.
我想我想表达的是
I guess what I'm trying to say is,
我不能否认我的过去
I'm not denying the person I was
和我干过的事
or the things I did,
因为我确实干了
because I did those things.
如果我能回到过去改变那些事
If I could go back and change what I did,
我一定会的  但我不能
I would, but I can't.
我能做的只是向你们发誓
What I can do is swear to you
我绝不会再成为过去的那个我
that I will never go back to being that person again.
你要拿走吉尔的财产是你过分了
You crossed the line when you took Jill's money.
不  迈克  我没有
No, Mike, I didn't,
但我现在打算过分一下了
but I'm about to cross it now.
你想知道什么是滥用权力是吗
You want to see abuse of power?
你的协议没了
Your deal is gone.
如果你的陈述做完了
If there are no other statements--
其实  我有话要说
Matter of fact, I would, uh, like to say a few words.
-你是哪位  -卡梅隆・丹尼斯
- And you are? - Cameron Dennis.
我是加洛先生一案当时的检察官
I was the district attorney at the time of Mr. Gallo's trial.
主席先生
Mr. Chairman,
丹尼斯先生要播放的录音带
Mr. Dennis is about to play a tape
是当时庭审的证据
from the original trial.
当时没有被承认
It wasn't admissible then,
现在也无权被承认
and it's not admissible now.
不  哈维  我是要读
No, Harvey, I'm going to read
加洛先生判刑听证会上
the transcript of your own words
你本人的原话记录
from Mr. Gallo's sentencing hearing.
弗兰克・加洛就是个人渣
"Frank Gallo is the scum of the Earth.
他是一个对自己所犯之罪
"He's a sociopath who has no remorse
毫无悔过之心的疯子
"for the things he's done,
他是个应该因为他所犯下的罪行
and he is an animal who deserves to be locked up
被终身监禁的人
for the rest of his miserable life."
我给你的豁免权是免除你被抓前
I gave you immunity for crimes you committed
所犯下的罪行
before you got caught.
但你的认罪协议上称
But your plea agreement says
没有执照的情况下你绝不会再次行使律师权力
you'll never practice law again without a license.
你现在就在监狱里行使着律师权力
You've been practicing law in here,
所以这就是
which means that's a crime
你被抓后的犯罪
that happened after you got caught.
胡扯
Bullshit.
凯文和吉尔知道我不是律师
Kevin and Jill both know that I'm not a lawyer.
你清楚我也清楚
You know that and I know that,
但如果你要斗
but if you fight it,
我就跟你在庭上斗两年
I will argue it in court for the next two years.
要是你不放弃这件事
And if you don't drop this thing,
那么在你刑满前你要能提前出来一天
you'll be lucky if they let you out a day
那都是你走运
before you were supposed to get out anyway.
主席先生  我要说
Mr. Chairman, I'm telling you,
弗兰克・加洛改邪归正了
Frank Gallo has changed.
我向听证席保证他没有
And I'm telling the board he hasn't changed.
他只是在勒索你
He's just trying to blackmail you.
谎话
That's a lie.
那你发誓这不是真的啊
Then take the stand and swear it's not true.
够了
That's enough.
斯佩克特先生  这是保释听证会  不是法庭
Mr. Specter, this is a parole hearing, not a court of law,
但如果他说的话是真的
but if there's any truth to what he's saying,
你必须说出来
we need to know.
那不是真的
It's not true.
很不幸  今天的会议
Unfortunately, this body
无权让你对这句话起誓
doesn't have the authority to swear you in,
但我会确保明天的会议有这个权力
but I'm going to make sure that we will tomorrow.
希望你能认真考虑
I'd like you to think long and hard about
明天要说什么
what you're gonna say then,
因为你必须为明天的话起誓
because you'll be saying it under oath.
迈克  我有事告诉你
Mike, I need to tell you what just happened.
我得先告诉你我这边的事
I need to tell you what happened first.
滥用权力  你疯啦
Abuse of power? Are you nuts?
我别无选择
It's the only play I have.
你唯一的选择是等待释放证明
Your only play is to walk out of here
然后离开这里
when your release comes through,
不是威胁要释放你的人
not threaten the guy who made that happen.
听着
Listen to me.
卡荷尔要冻结他们的个人财产
Cahill is seizing their personal assets.
他就是要一砖一砖拆了他们的房子
Yeah, I don't care if he takes their house apart
我也不在乎
brick by brick.
哈维  要不是卡荷尔凯文根本就
Harvey, Kevin wouldn't even be in here in the first place
不会进来
if it weren't for Cahill.
不  迈克  凯文进来
No, Mike, Kevin wouldn't be here
是因为该告发萨特的时候他自己没这么做
if he had chosen to roll over on Sutter in the first place.
而且多亏他没这么做
And it's a good thing he didn't,
否则你就得和加洛一起
because you'd be stuck in here with Gallo
被困在这儿两年了
for the next two years.
我不在意加洛
I don't care about Gallo.
你得在意一下  因为他还没出去
Well, you should, because he's not out yet,
而且有卡梅隆・丹尼斯在
and if it's up to Cameron Dennis,
他恐怕出不去了
he's not getting out.
什么
What?
卡梅隆听说了我给加洛争取保释的事
Cameron got wind that I'm trying to get Gallo parole.
现在我得想办法
And now I got to think of something
或者明天做伪证
or perjure myself tomorrow,
否则他就得坐穿牢底了
or he's gonna end up right back in here.
那我们就更不能把凯文留在里面了
Well, that's even more reason why we can't leave Kevin behind.
如果加洛出不去  我出去了
If Gallo doesn't get out and I do,
他第一个要报复的就是凯文
the first person he's gonna go after is Kevin.
我同意这件事时可不知道会有人被害死
And I didn't sign on to get someone killed.
不  你同意的是让你自己出狱
No, you signed on to get yourself out.
现在如果你不放弃这桩诉讼的话
Now if you don't drop this suit,
卡荷尔一定会威胁取消交易
Cahill's gonna threaten to pull your deal.
怎么了
What?
他已经这么做了
He already did.
那我们还这么讨论的意义何在
Then why are we still having this conversation?
因为我说了  我手上只剩下
Because like I said, this is the only card
这招可用了
I have left to play.
所以如果你要我放弃这个
So if you want me to drop this,
你要让卡荷尔秉持正义把凯文弄出去
you get Cahill to do the right thing and get Kevin out.
我不得不说  作为一个主修公司法的律师
I have to say, for someone who practices corporate law,
你可以说是深谙上诉法院之道
you know your way around an appeals court.
谢谢
Thank you,
但是你来这里的目的应该不是想招募我吧
but you're not here to offer me a job as a prosecutor,
你是来给伦纳德・贝利交易机会的
you're here to offer Leonard Bailey a deal.
-所以切入正题吧  -面对现实吧
- So let's get to it. - Let's face it.
你或许拿到了他原律师的宣誓书
You may have that affidavit from his original attorney,
然而你没有DNA  没有不在场证人
but you have no DNA, no alibi,
而且我猜其他证据你也根本没有
and I'm guess not a hell of a lot else.
我有的  拉里
What I have, Larry,
就是一个它每多拖一天
is a case that will embarrass you personally
你就越颜面扫地的案子
every day it drags on,
因为当初让它上庭的律师就是你
because you were the one that tried it in the first place.
所以赶紧给个刑期  别耽误我工作
So give me a number, so I can get on with my day.
贝利再蹲十年牢  我们皆大欢喜
Bailey does ten more years, and we all go home.
你说十年  其实心理预期是九年吧
When you say ten, you mean nine,
而且你我都清楚我能压到七年
and we both know I can get you down to seven,
所以就五年吧
so let's just say five.
但是我这么说吧
But I'll tell you what.
如果你让他现在就出狱的话
You let my client walk right now,
你的梦想就能实现
and you get your dream.
我们可以不重开此案
We don't open this case at all.
没门儿
No way.
七年刑期  爱要不要
Seven years, take it or leave it.
24小时内给我答复
Offer's good 24 hours.
不  我们不能接受
No, this is unacceptable.
这是你能得到的最好交易
Well, it's the best you're gonna do.
不  最好的交易是让我的委托人
No, the best I'm going to do
因为一个他没有犯下的罪行
is get my client exonerated
被无罪释放
from a crime he didn't commit
并让你颜面扫地
and make you look like a fool.
那放马过来
Then bring it on.
但法律层面讲你必须把交易条件告知委托人
But you're legally obligated to present my offer to your client.
并且提醒他  如果他这次再输
And remind him, if he loses again,
六十天后他就没命了
in 60 days his life is over.
谢谢  比尔
Thanks, Bill.
肖恩  迈克的交易怎么回事
Sean, what's going on with Mike's deal?
啥
Excuse me?
它怎么还没有被批准
Why hasn't it come through yet?
大概是文件处理过程耽搁了吧
Oh, there must've been a mix-up in the paperwork.
扯淡
Bullshit.
你把它延后了是因为他威胁说要告你
You're holding it up because he's threatening to sue you.
对  你说得没错
Oh, you're right. I am.
而且如果他不撤诉并答应不再搅和这事
And if doesn't drop this thing and agree to walk away,
我就把他的交易作废
I'm gonna dump his deal altogether.
肖恩  通过他的交易吧
Sean, let his deal go through.
一旦他出狱
Once he gets out,
他不会把这件事跟进到底的
he's not gonna follow through on this thing.
噢  肖恩  你别威胁他
"Oh, Sean, put down your gun.
我保证迈克不威胁你
"I promise Mike'll put his down too.
而且我们的言辞值得信任
"And you can trust the both of us,
因为我们以前从来没对你撒过谎
'cause neither of us has ever lied to you before."
如果你不信任我们
If you didn't trust us,
从一开始你就不会来找我
you never would've come to me in the first place.
如果我一早就知道结局如此
If I had known this is how it was going to end,
我就不会找你们
I never would have.
你个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
你要什么我们都他妈给你摆平了
We got you every goddamn thing you wanted.
你们对我的要求我也做到了
I held up my end of the bargain,
更别提我还帮吉尔・米勒要到了豁免
not to mention the fact I gave immunity to Jill Miller
而我根本不用做到这个程度
when I didn't have to.
瞎扯淡你说你根本不用做到这个程度
Bullshit you didn't have to.
她帮你赢了案子
She made your case,
而且是迈克冒着生命危险帮你争取到她的
and Mike risked his life to get her for you.
为了让我把那孩子弄出狱
You had no problem asking me
你让我冒多大险眼都不眨一下
to risk everything to get that kid out,
而我也这么做了
and I did it.
现在你这个过河拆桥的混蛋
And now that ungrateful son of a bitch
居然想反咬一口
wants to bite the hand that feeds him,
我打算直接把他晚餐撤掉
I'm gonna take away his dinner
告诉他谁才是他主子
and show him who his master is.
肖恩  拜托你了
Sean, please.
加洛有可能要继续坐牢的
Gallo might not get out,
迈克就得陪着他坐穿牢底
and Mike's gonna be stuck in there with him.
这更有理由让他不要再找我麻烦
Well, all the more reason he should put down his gun
乖乖出狱了
and walk out that f---ing door.
杰西卡  进来吧
Jessica, come in.
抱歉我突然就这么过来了
I'm sorry to drop by unannounced,
但是我有要事要和你谈
but I need to talk to you.
不不  我很抱歉是我早退了
No, no, I'm sorry that I had to leave a little bit early.
我只是想在迈克回来前把家收拾好
I just wanted to get the place ready for when Mike gets home.
那我长话短说
Then I won't take up much of your time.
他们给了伦纳德・贝利一个交易
They offered Leonard Bailey a deal.
-多长时间  -七年
- How long? - Seven years.
但是我也许能把刑期减到五年
But I can probably get them down to five.
再为他没犯过的罪蹲多五年牢
Five more years for a crime he didn't commit
正义并没有得到伸张啊
doesn't seem really fair.
然而输掉一个二审
And losing a retrial
最后横死狱中也不公平啊
and dying in prison doesn't seem fair either.
-但我们并不一定会输  -不是的
- But we're not gonna lose. - That's not true.
我们有很大几率会输
There's a good chance we will.
-杰西卡  -瑞秋
- Jessica-- - Rachel.
陪审团捉摸不定的
Juries are unpredictable.
即使他们被要求无视之前的情况
Even if they'd been told to disregard something,
他们也心里清楚他曾经被判有罪过
they know he was convicted before.
这是一个让他能够死里逃生的机会
This is a chance at getting his life back.
那他劫后余生的生活又会是如何呢
What kind of life are we talking about?
他仍然会被看作是一个罪犯
He's still going to be seen as a murderer
甚至他最亲的母亲一样的人都会这么认为
even by the closest thing he has to a mother.
那我也不能让他为一个不是他的罪行被杀
I'm not gonna let him die for a crime he didn't commit.
我也不想让他死啊
I don't want to let him die either.
我想争取救他出狱
I want to fight to get him out.
然而我不认为你有足够的经验
And I don't think you've been practicing law long enough
做出这个判断
to make that call.
瑞秋  这对他来说已经是胜利了
Rachel, this is a win for him.
摆正心态
So get your mind right
我们到牢里必须统一论调
so that we can walk into that prison on the same page.
哈维  除非你来这里是告诉我
Harvey, unless you're here to tell me
你想通了释放这个畜生是不对的
you've come to your senses about this animal,
否则我们没什么话说
this is gonna be a short conversation.
我是来给你这个的
I came here to show you this.
这是什么
What is this?
这是一份来自全国最好的
It's a three-year surveillance agreement
侦探事务所的3年监视协议
with the best detective agency in the state.
你凭什么认为仅仅由于你对他进行了监视
And what makes you think just because you follow him,
就能阻止他继续犯罪了呢
it's gonna stop him from committing crimes?
卡梅隆  我不能让他跟迈克待在同一座监狱
Cameron, I can't have him in there with Mike.
据我耳闻  迈克要出狱了
Well, from what I heard, Mike's getting out.
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
你这话什么意思  没那么简单
What do you mean, it's not that simple?
证监会对迈克的狱友  也就是帮他脱狱的人
The SEC pulled some shady shit with Mike's cellmate,
耍了些阴险的手段
the same guy that helped get Mike out in the first place.
现在迈克在跟他们叫板
Now Mike's been playing chicken with them,
如果他不放弃
and if he doesn't drop it,
他们是不会让他出狱的
they're not gonna let him out.
让我先搞搞清楚
Let me get this straight.
你想让我作伪证
You want me to perjure myself
这样你就能把这个禽兽弄出监狱
so you can put this monster on the street
因为你的死党想要对抗当局
because your sidekick wants to fight The Man?
别跟我玩这套
Don't play that shit with me.
你不守规矩这么多年了
You've been crossing lines for years,
你连一分钟都没有失眠过
and you didn't lose a minute's sleep over it.
你说的对极了我没有
You're damn right I didn't,
因为我是为了把加洛这样的家伙关起来
because I was doing it to put guys like Gallo away,
而不是让他们晚上在外游荡
not let them wander around at night
仅仅指望某个拿着拍立得的胖子
hoping some fat guy with a Polaroid
确保他们不去谋杀其他人
is gonna keep him from murdering somebody else.
那如果他要谋杀的那个人是我呢
And what if that person he was gonna be murdering was me?
因为迈克对于我来说
Because Mike is to me
就是你眼中曾经的我
what I used to be to you.
那就说服他去做正确的事
Then convince him to do the right thing
就像你曾经说服我一样
like you tried to do once with me.
因为  哈维
Because, Harvey,
你知道你为加洛做的事是错的
you know what you're doing with Gallo is wrong.
你不会相信这事的
You're not gonna believe this,
但瑞秋打来找你了
but I got Rachel on the phone for you.
-什么  -没错
- What? - Yeah.
她那天晚上拿到了我的号码
She had my number from the other night,
她想跟你聊聊
and she wants to talk to you.
谢谢
Thanks.
还有迈克  如果你是为了我留在这里
And Mike, if you're staying in here for me,
别这么做
don't do it.
上帝啊  我等不及想见你了
God, I can't wait to see you.
我也等不及想见你了
I can't wait to see you either.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
是的  我
Yeah, I, um--
我只是想跟你聊聊我那个死刑委托人
I just wanted to talk to you about my death row client.
要我怎么帮忙
How can I help?
他们给我们提供了一份协议
They offered us a deal
让他在5年后出狱
for him to get out in five years,
杰西卡想接下来
and Jessica wants to take it.
但我想为他搏一下
But I want to fight for him.
让我猜猜  她想统一战线
Let me guess, she wants to present a united front.
是的
She does.
我不确定我还能怎么帮你
Well, I'm not sure how I can help you
我想我只能告诉你相信自己
other than to tell you to follow your gut.
你可以让我理解坐牢是种怎样的体验
You can help me understand what it's like to be in prison.
你最好表现得令人信服
You better be convincing out there.
加洛  为了让我们之间扯平
Gallo, I'm about to sell my soul
我都要出卖自己的灵魂了
to make us even,
所以你给我坐下  闭嘴
so sit down, shut up,
以及确保今天之后
and make sure that after today,
我再也看不到你这张脸
I never see your face again.
斯佩克特先生
Mr. Specter.
你准备好宣誓了吗
Are you ready to be sworn in?
假释委员会的各位女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen of the board,
在斯佩克特先生发表证词之前
before Mr. Specter testifies,
我想代表当局
I'd like to present Michael Ross
引入迈克尔・罗斯作为证人
as a witness on behalf of the state.
主席先生  这次听证会被召集的原因是
Mr. Chairman, this hearing was called
以便我能
so that I could--
你会有机会发表意见的  斯佩克特先生
You'll get your chance, Mr. Specter.
我想听听这位年轻人想说点什么
I'd like to hear what the young man has to say.
我可以让他宣誓
I can have him sworn in.
没这个必要
That won't be necessary.
罗斯先生  你是丹伯里联邦监狱的一位犯人
Mr. Ross, you are an inmate here at Danbury,
这个说法正确吗
is that correct?
是的  我因为无证从事律师执业
Yes, I'm serving a two-year sentence
正在服两年的刑期
for practicing law without a license.
你此前在哪家律所工作
And what firm did you work at?
我为斯佩克特先生工作
I worked for Mr. Specter.
你知道最初就是斯佩克特先生
Are you aware that Mr. Specter
起诉的弗兰克・加洛吗
originally prosecuted Frank Gallo?
是的  我知道
Yes, I am.
是谁告诉你这件事的
And who made you aware of it?
弗兰克・加洛
Frank Gallo did.
他是随便顺带提起了这事吗
He just mentioned something in passing?
不
No.
不是  我来这的第一晚
No, on my first night here,
加洛先生贿赂了一位狱警
Mr. Gallo bribed a guard
这样他就能到我牢房里来
so that he could get into my cell,
然后他假装是我同监室的狱友
and then he pretended to be my roommate.
在获得我的信任之后
And after getting me to trust him,
他才告诉我说从他坐牢
he told me that he had been trying
第一天起他就一直在想办法
to get revenge on Harvey Specter
向哈维・斯佩克特复仇
since the day he'd been put away.
然后他告诉我他现在要通过找我麻烦
Then he told me that now he was gonna get revenge on Harvey
来向哈维复仇
by coming after me.
你清楚他说的"找你麻烦"是什么意思吗
Was it clear to you what he meant by "coming after you"?
他说他要杀了我
He said he would kill me.
事实上  第二天晚上他就拿刀来杀我
In fact, he tried to shiv me the second night,
但被一位狱警阻止了
but a guard stopped him.
再问一个问题
Just one more question.
斯佩克特知道你受到的这些威胁吗
Was Mr. Specter aware of these threats?
他当然知道
Of course he was.
不然你觉得他为什么想保释加洛
Why else do you think he's been trying to get Gallo parole?
谢谢  罗斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Ross.
斯佩克特先生  你准备宣誓
Mr. Specter, are you prepared
驳回这些证词吗
to refute this testimony under oath?
不  法官大人
No, Your Honor.
我不准备
I'm not.
休庭5分钟
We'll take a five-minute recess.
你是故意的
You did this.
你一直都跟他串通一气
You were in on it with him the whole time.
你说对了  我是故意的
You're right. I did.
所以你有事冲着我来  别找他麻烦
So you come after me, not him.
我会冲着你们两个来
I'm coming after both of you,
但我会先找他麻烦
but I'm coming after him sooner.
你躲不过我的
Hey, you can't hide from me.
我不需要躲你
Oh, I don't need to hide from you,
因为我今天就要出狱了
'cause it turns out I'm getting out today.
对此你无能为力
And there's nothing you can do about it.
5年还是挺长一段时间
Five years is still a long time.
是的  没错
Yes, it is.
但你出狱之后就自由了
But then you walk out of here a free man.
自由了  但并不是无辜的
A free man, but not an innocent one.
你仍然是无辜的  伦纳德
You're still innocent, Leonard,
不管这个世界怎么看
whether the world sees it that way or not.
但如果整个世界都认为我是个有罪的杀人犯
But if the world thinks I'm a convicted murderer,
那还不如让我死在这里
then I might as well die in here,
因为外面根本没有我的容身之地
because there's not gonna be a life out there for me anyway.
没人说过那很轻松
No one said it was going to be easy.
但为你没犯过的罪而死
But there's no point in dying for a crime
是毫无意义的
you didn't commit.
我觉得你没搞明白
I don't think you understand.
我做这件事不是为了活下去
I'm not doing this just to stay alive.
我是为了有一天当我敲开我孩子的家门
I'm doing this so one day I can knock on my kid's door,
他们能知道他们的爸爸是无辜的
and they'll know their father is an innocent man.
若我接受这个交易  这个愿望就没法实现了
If I take this deal, that's never gonna happen.
如果你不接受
If you don't take it,
它也很可能没法实现
it may never happen either.
你今天话很少  你怎么看
You're pretty quiet. What do you think?
我认为
I--I think that Jessica
杰西卡比我更有经验
has a lot more experience than I do.
我没问你这个
That's not what I asked you.
我想知道你认为我该做什么
I want to know what you think I should do.
伦纳德  你出去的可能性
Leonard, the odds of you getting out--
我说了我想听她的想法
I said I want to know what she thinks.
我觉得你该继续抗争
I think you should fight.
那我就这么做
Then that's what I'm going to do.
该死  我说过我们要站在统一口径的
Goddamn it, I said we need to be on the same page.
他问我怎么想
He asked me what I thought.
我不能对他撒谎
I'm not gonna lie to him.
我真没想到罗伯特・赞恩的女儿
I never would've thought Robert Zane's daughter
会这么天真
would be so naive.
天真
Naive?
我刚开始要相信
I was actually starting to believe
你是真的在乎这个案子
that you cared about this case,
但你唯一关心的就是
but the only thing that you care about
把它赶紧了结
is putting it to bed as quickly as possible.
你还真敢说啊
How dare you?
权衡利弊不等于不关心
Playing the odds isn't the same as not caring.
也许是这样  但杰西卡
Maybe not, but Jessica,
从我工作开始就一直在你身边
I have watched you my whole career,
这是第一次在面对战斗时
and this is the first time that you've ever
你选择逃避
backed away from a fight.
那是因为你从来没有看到过
That's because you've never seen me fight
我为某个命悬一线的人战斗
when someone's life is on the line.
-你  -没错
-You-- - That's right.
我以前也遇到过这种情况
I was in a situation like this once before.
我当时的做法和你现在希望的一样
I did what you want me to do now.
结果我们输了  那件事让我痛彻心扉
We lost, and it ripped me to shreds.
所以当我告诉你我的经验远比你多时
So when I tell you I have a lot more experience than you,
你要相信我
believe it.
杰西卡  我很遗憾
Jessica, I'm sorry...
你之前输过一个这样的案子
that you lost a case like this before.
但要帮助伦纳德不该是去说服他
But the way to help Leonard is not to convince him
接受一个让他活着也了无意义的交易
to take some deal that he can't live with.
而是应该去争取他愿意为之活下去的东西
It is to fight to give him something worth living for.
你都干了些什么
What the hell did you do?
我只是说到做到
I did what I said I'd do.
我要让那个禽兽继续待在牢里
I kept that animal behind bars.
我说的是迈克
I'm talking about Mike.
你跟他达成了交易  对吧
You cut a deal with him, didn't you?
不是  哈维  是他和我达成了交易
No, Harvey, he cut a deal with me.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你告诉他我也卷入其中之后
After you told him I was involved with this thing,
他就给我打电话问我能不能
he called me and asked if I could do something
帮帮他的朋友
about his friend Kevin.
我说我会想想办法
I said I'd look into it,
但要他替我做件事
but he'd have to do something for me.
所以你就胡乱承诺
And so you made some bullshit promise with him
骗他这么做
in exchange for doing that.
我没乱说
It wasn't bullshit.
我不替美国证监会工作  哈维
I don't work for the SEC, Harvey.
我把真正的罪犯送进监狱
I put away real criminals.
这个把凯文・米勒送进监狱的人
And the person who put away Kevin Miller
知道只要能把一个谋杀犯关在监狱里
knows that it's worth it to let a drunk driver out,
去释放一个酒驾司机还是值得的
as long as it means keeping a murderer in.
然后就不管迈克会怎么样了是吗
And to hell with what happens to Mike.
他做这件事的时候就知道后果
Hey, he went in there with his eyes wide open,
而且加洛根本没法对他下手
and Gallo can't do anything to him anyway,
因为他今晚就出来了
because he's getting out tonight.
你还不懂是吗
Don't you get it?
迈克今晚就不安全
Mike's not gonna be safe tonight
以后也不会了  因为加洛不管在不在牢里
or any other night, because Gallo can get to him
都能找上他
whether he's behind bars or not.
就像我说的  哈维
Well, like I said, Harvey,
他自己本来就清楚后果
he knew what he was getting into,
但他还是找了我
and he came to me.
你一整天都去哪了
Hey, where you been all day?
履行我的诺言
Been doing what I said I was gonna do.
我要把你弄出去
I'm getting you out.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding.
我看起来像是开玩笑吗
Do I look like I'm kidding?
那就拿起电话  打给吉尔
So take that phone of yours, call Jill,
告诉她你马上就回家了
and tell her you're coming home--
就在今晚
tonight.
我都不敢相信
I don't believe it.
你真的把我弄出狱了
You really did that for me?
是的
I did.
那你呢
What about you?
我和你一起走
I'm getting out with you.
什么
What?
我只是不敢相信我今晚就能给孩子盖被子
I just can't believe I'm gonna be tucking my kids
哄他们上床睡觉
into bed tonight.
我不敢相信我就要见到瑞秋了
I can't believe I'm gonna see Rachel.
我真的不胜感激  迈克
I can't thank you enough, Mike.
好了  我们走吧
All right, let's go.
也是够慢的
It's about time.
没有你  罗斯  只有米勒
Not you, Ross. Just Miller.
什么  你说什么呢
What? What are you talking about?
我也要出去的
I'm getting out too.
我在服从命令  我得到的命令就是带他出去
I'm following orders, and my orders are to bring him out.
不是你
Not you.
这是你干的
You did this.
我什么都没干
I didn't do shit.
但我绝对会好好利用下这个机会的
But I sure as hell am gonna take advantage of it.
迈克不走我也不走
I'm not leaving without Mike.
你必须走
Yeah, you are.
而且我不管是不是得亲手把你从这
And I don't care if I have to drag your ass
一路拖出去
out of here myself.
你现在就得走
You're leaving right now.
哈维  很好  你来了
Harvey, good, you're here.
到底怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
你说如果迈克撤诉
You said you'd reinstate the deal
你就恢复交易
if Mike dropped his suit.
-我做到了  -胡说
- And I did. - Bullshit.
你撤销他的交易  现在他一个人在牢里
You pulled his deal, and now he's in there all alone.
要是你现在不拿起电话
Now if you don't pick up the phone--
哈维  我没撤销什么交易
Harvey, I didn't pull anything.
-什么  -迈克打给我
- What? - Mike called me.
他让我把他的文书工作推迟
He told me to hold off his paperwork
直到明天早晨
until tomorrow morning.
那他为什么要那么做呢  肖恩
Why the hell would he do that, Sean?
因为他有个计划  而且不希望你知道
Because he has a plan, and he didn't want you to know.
我不在乎他的计划是什么  你
I don't care what his plan is. You--
听着  他不想你知道  ?是因为他不希望
Listen, he doesn't want you to know, because he didn't
你阻止他  现在你已经无法阻止他了
want you to stop it, and now that you can't,
所以我们得一起帮他搞定这件事
he's gonna need our help to bring it home.
谢谢你  金波
Thanks, Jimbo.
能不能麻烦你  我想和迈克
Why don't you go ahead and give me and Mike here
单独谈谈
a little privacy?
你想怎样  加洛
What do you want, Gallo?
你在我的假释听证会上
That's a stupid question
说了那些话后  现在居然还问我想干嘛
after what you pulled at my parole hearing.
-你不应该被假释  -你也一样
- You didn't deserve to get out. - Neither did you.
而且你现在没机会了
And now you're not gonna.
怎么  你要让我死在牢房里吗
What, you're gonna kill me in this cell?
外面有警卫
There are guards out there.
你还是不明白  是么
It just doesn't sink in for you, does it?
那些警卫都是我的人
Those guards out there work for me.
懂吗  迈克  我不会让上次的事情
See, Mike, I wasn't gonna let what happened last time
再次重演
happen this time.
这次不会再有人在最后一刻来救你了
No one's gonna come run helping you at the last second,
因为他们都被关在狱室里
because they're all locked up tight in their bunks.
讽刺的是
And irony of ironies,
因为很久以前的什么罪犯人权诉讼
because of some prisoners' rights lawsuit way back when,
所以牢房内都没有监控
there are no cameras in cells.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
等待已经结束了
No, the time for waiting is done.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no.
你难道不想知道这里有监控吗
I meant, don't you want to hear about the camera that's in here?
-胡说  -笑一个  混蛋
- Bullshit. - Smile, you son of a bitch.
不
No!
你不会留下来就是为了这个吧
You did not keep yourself in here just to do this.
是的  弗兰克  就是为了这个
Yeah, Frank, I did.
现在  那些没被你收买的警卫
And now all those guards that aren't in your pocket--
都在看着呢
they're watching this right now.
警卫站离这间牢房六十英尺
And it's 60 feet from that guard station to this cell,
如果我算的没错的话
so if I calculated correctly,
他们已经铐住了金波
they've got Jimbo in cuffs,
现在应该来开门了
and they're gonna be opening that door right now.
放下刀  退后  加洛
Drop that knife and step back, Gallo.
你这个垃圾
Oh, you piece of shit!
你还是死定了
Doesn't change anything.
呵呵  咱们走着瞧
Yeah, yeah, yeah. We'll see about that.
路易
Louis?
塔拉
Tara.
我从来没发现这里晚上原来这么美
I've never seen how beautiful it is in here at night.
美吗
Beautiful.
我想跟你说说今天的事
I want to tell you what happened.
请说
Please.
约书亚之所以会来
The reason Joshua came to town
是因为我告诉了他你的事
is that I told him about you--
我们的事
about us.
所以你和他分手了吗
So did you break up with him?
路易  他向我求婚了
Louis, he asked me to marry him.
你的回答呢
And what'd you say?
我跟他说
I told him...
我不能嫁给他
I couldn't marry him
因为我对另一个男人有着特殊的感觉
while I felt this way about another man.
所以我们现在怎么样了
So where does that leave us?
我希望应该是你想要的那样了
I hope it leaves us where you want us to be.
是的
It does.
完美
It absolutely does.
你是来给我送面包和水的吗
You here to bring me bread and water?
要我说了算  我会让你饿着
If it was up to me, I'd let you starve.
我猜  你是来告诉我他们又要
Let me guess: you're here to tell me how much time
给我加多少刑期的
they're tacking onto my sentence.
但我不在乎
Well, it doesn't matter how much.
因为我还是能报复他
'Cause I'm gonna get to him,
也能报复你
and I'm gonna get to you.
抱歉  弗兰克  但是我们没有要给你
Sorry, Frank, but you're not getting anything
加刑期
tacked onto your sentence.
给你的离别礼物  是让你回你来的地方去
Your parting gift is going back to the maximum security hellhole
最高监管监狱
you came from.
不可能
No way.
你没权力这么做
You don't have the power to make that happen.
是的  我没权力
You're right, I don't.
但是我证监会的朋友可以
But my friend at the SEC sure does.
你为什么这么不开心呢  弗兰克
Why are you so upset, Frank?
是不是因为
Does it have anything to do with the fact
那里的犯人都知道
that every inmate in there
你做了线人
knows that you're an informant,
而你能活过第一晚  就算走大运了
and you'll be lucky to make it through your first night?
你觉得我怕吗
You think I'm afraid?
我觉得你现在肯定屎都吓出来了
I think you're shitting in your pants right now,
所以我觉得你应该会对第二个选择
which is why I think you'll be interested
很有兴趣
in what's behind door number two.
那就是你安分待在丹伯里监狱
You stay here at Danbury,
就再蹲个五年
you do five more years,
哪怕迈克只是过得有一点不舒服
and if Mike so much as gets a pebble in his shoe,
你就只剩第一种选择了
you go back to door number one.
我就当你这一脸愤恨是答应了
I'll take that hatred in your face as a yes,
因为你现在跟我上次把你送进来时候
'cause it's the same look you had
表情一模一样
the last time I put you away.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
瑞秋呢
Where's Rachel?
我是来跟你说有人要来看你了
I'm just here to tell you you're about to get a visitor.
你说服了我阿姨来看我吗
You convinced my aunt to come see me?
没有  我没能说服她
No, I couldn't convince her.
但我找到了你的女儿
But I was able to track down your daughter.
什么
What?
你没听错
You heard right.
玛雅就在外面
Maya's right outside.
我需要静静
I'm gonna need a moment.
当然
Of course.
我知道你这么做只是为了让她劝我接受协议
I know you only did this so she'll tell me to take the deal,
但还是谢谢你
but thank you.
伦纳德  她根本不知道协议的事
Leonard, she doesn't even know about the deal.
那你是怎么说服她来的
Then what'd you tell her to get her to come?
我跟她说我们发现了新的证据
I told her we found new evidence that her father
可以证明她父亲的清白
is an innocent man.
而她应该在我们上庭前
And she should hear it from you
先听你亲口告诉她
before we go to court to prove it.
所以你真的觉得我做的是对的
So you do think I'm doing the right thing?
说实话  我并不是很清楚
Honestly, I don't know if you are or you're not.
但我知道的是  如果真的在乎某个人
But what I do know is, when you care about someone,
无论如何你都会支持他
you have their back either way.
你准备好了吗
You're ready?
进来吧
Come on.
爸爸
Hi, Daddy.
宝贝儿
Hey, sweetheart.
成了吗
Did it work?
成了
It worked.
我们做到了
We did it.
做到了
We did.
我们走吧
Come on, let's get out of here.
对了  还有件事
Oh, one more thing,
有人等不及你回家了
someone couldn't wait for you to get home.